[Brooks]
Dotsub's number one mission is to ensure
that video can be communicated
to as many people as possible in the world.
[dotsub™]
[Any Video Any Language]
[Michael]
Seventy-five percent of the world
doesn't speak any English at all,
and people emotionally connect with,
engage with,
enjoy stories and communication
in their own language.
>> [David] We are
an online video captioning
and translation platform.
[Michael]
We received a patent for the process
of a browser-based
or cloud-based tool
to enable time coding to be done
by a browser
in a collaborative way, and then subtitling
and captioning be done from a browser.
We created something
called the VLMS,
the Video Language Management System.
[Brooks]
Dotsub's Video Language Management System
is a proprietary system
for tracking and reviewing
and assigning your translation work,
where it empowers
our enterprise users
to have complex workflows
that meet their business needs.
>> [Michael] The first thing that we do
is create a time coded caption
in the source language of the video,
and then enable that
to be edited or reviewed collaboratively
by anyone in the world
with granular permissioning
down to the caption level.
[David]
We allow any video to be indexed,
understood, to be accessible,
and to be, really, more engaging
for anybody around the world.
[Dave]
Having a translation—either a caption
or a voiceover—
is a significantly more efficient way
of getting that message across,
and a much more emotionally inclusive way—
a much better way
of communicating
with the people around the world.
[Peter]
Most of Dotsub's customers
come to us
with a specific need.
They're trying to use their video assets
in ways to reach new markets,
new audiences,
make it more useful,
repurpose it, have it go further,
have it touch more people.
[Dave]
We can provide the, A) the knowledge
and B) the technology
to do it.
The way we work is very much
like like a concierge service.
It never ceases to amaze me
the amount of work
what people within Dotsub will go to
to make sure that a customer
gets their work done properly.
[Brooks]
Yeah, and making sure the platform's robust enough.
We have two nines uptimes—
it's something we're very proud of,
that we're able to offer such a product
to our end users
at such high availability.
>> [Clara] The idea that you can integrate
your existing account
on an OVP with Dotsub
means that you do not need
to manage files.
The video that is already
on an online video platform,
what you do is you tag it,
we bring it to Dotsub
without you having to do
anything else.
Captions are done at Dotsub.
Translations are done at Dotsub.
When they are published,
they are sent back to the OVP.
So if the video living in the OVP
is already on a website,
captions will go there live.
>> [Brooks] We can actually seamlessly bring
in your video content,
automatically caption it,
translate it to all your target languages,
upload the result
back to your OVP
without a single touch.
I think that's the greatest value added.
>> [Peter] The final review stop
gives people the assurance
that the quality that they want
is under their control
and will be delivered on time.
[Clara]
We want to connect people
from different parts of the world.
We give people the tools
to do what they do best.
[Brooks]
Scalability—always looking
to serve not just one user
but a million users.
[Peter] Our biggest customers—
ten out of the Fortune 50 companies
that we work with on a regular basis—
what they're looking for is ease,
speed, and quality
that they can rely on.
[Clara] You can control when things go live
by publishing them.
When they get published here,
they appear there.
It saves a lot of time
and saves a lot of money.
[Brooks] Ensuring we're future proof
to the next level.
Thirty-five, 40% of our users lately
turning towards mobile.
[Clara] We have captioners and translators
all over the world.
[Brooks] Taking pride
in the product that we deliver to the end user.
[Dave]
It's a very nice feeling to be a member
of a club that feels so passionately
about the things that you feel passionately about.
You find yourself in a group of people
who are passionate
about doing a good job.
>> [Clara] I have the most amazing team
of project managers.
[dotsub™]
[Any Video Any Language]
[Clara]
I had no idea this was even possible.
It's wonderful, really.
>> [Peter] It is fantastic.
>> [Clara] [laughing]
>> [Dave] [laughing]
>> [Peter] [laughing]
>> [Brooks] [laughing]
>> [David Thank you very much.
>> [Michael] So why don't we start this again?
[Dotsub]
[In order of appearance:]
[Brooks Lyrette] [Michael Smolens]
[David Orban] [Dave Bryant]
[Peter Crosby] [Clara Garcia]
[Directed, edited and produced by David Orban]
[Music]
["Adventures of the Deaf Dreamer"]
["Cherry"] [licensed under Creative Commons Attribution
by Josh Woodward]
[Copyright © 2015 Dotsub]
[dotsub.com]